Richard Hendriks

## Richard Hendriks

## Programmer

2712 Broadway St, CA 94115, San Francisco, California US

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

#### **SKILLS**

## Web Development Compression Master html css javascript mpeg mp4 gif

## WORK EXPERIENCE (1)

## **CEO/President at Pied Piper**

December 2013 - December 2014

https://piedpiper.com

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores<sup>™</sup> that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

#### VOLUNTEER

## Teacher at CoderDojo

January 2012 - January 2013

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

### https://coderdojo.com/

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

### EDUCATION (1)

## Bachelor Information Technology at University of Oklahoma

2011 - 2014

db1101 - basic sql cs2011 - java introduction

**Grade:** 4.0

#### **AWARDS**

# Digital Compression Pioneer Award at Techcrunch 2014 There is no spoon.

### **PROJECTS**

## Video compression for 3d media in Hooli

1 October 2014

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

## LANGUAGES

## English

Native speaker

### **INTERESTS**

## Wildlife

ferrets unicorns

## **REFERENCES**

"It is my pleasure to recommend Richard, his performance working as a consultant for Main St. Company proved that he will be a valuable addition to any company."

Erlich Bachman